# **Hyeonmin Lee**

# **Network Security Researcher**

• hyeonmin-lee.github.io in hyeonminlee1110

✓ min0921110@gmail.com

I am a postdoctoral researcher at Seoul National University. My research interests lie in network security including DNS security, Email security, and TLS. I have published five papers, three of which were published in top-tier conferences including USENIX Security and The Web Conference (formerly WWW). Also, I have participated in (or led) more than ten research projects with institutions such as Virginia Tech, Rochester Institute of Technology, University of Twente, KAIST, SIDN Labs, NLnet Labs, etc.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher, Network Convergence and Security Lab

Seoul National University

Apr 2022 - Present Seoul, South Korea

Expert Research Personnel\*, Network Convergence and Security Lab

Mar 2019 — Feb 2022

Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea

\*Military service combined with a Ph.D. program where the service is fulfilled through research on technology.

Visiting Student, The Center for Cybersecurity

May 2019 — Aug 2019

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY, United States

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D., Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea)

Mar 2016 — Feb 2022

- o [Ph.D. Thesis] "Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?"
- o [Advisors] Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (Seoul National University) and Prof. Taejoong "Tijay" Chung (Virginia Tech)

B.S., Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea) Visiting Student, Information Technology, Uppsala University, (Uppsala, Sweden)

Mar 2011 — Feb 2016

Fall 2014

**PUBLICATIONS (SELECTED)** 

### [C3] ZTLS: A DNS-based Approach to Zero Round Trip in TLS handshake

TheWebConf'23

- o Sangwon Lim, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Hyunsoo Kim, Hyunwoo Lee, Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon
- o In Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference 2023, Austin, United States, Apr 2023

#### [C2] Under the Hood of DANE mismanagement in SMTP

**USENIX Security'22** 

- o Hyeonmin Lee, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung
- o In Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2022

#### [C1] A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

**USENIX Security'20** 

- o Hyeonmin Lee, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung
- o In Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2020

#### RESEARCH PROJECT EXPERIENCE (SELECTED)

#### A Study for the Future-oriented DANE-based Web Architecture to Solve Problems in the Current TLS-based Web Ecosystem Primary Investigator Sep 2022 – Present

(Funded by Post-Doctoral Domestic and Overseas Training Program - National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF))

- o [Role] As a primary investigator, I am conducting an overall project. I analyze how the Web ecosystem will be changed if the Web adopts the DANE protocol for communication peer authentication.
- o [Keywords] Web, Transport Layer Security (TLS), Authentication, DANE

#### Research on Secure DNS and Privacy aware Packet Filtering Technology

System Designer, Programmer

Aug 2022 — Present

(Funded by Samsung Electronics)

- o [Role] As a postdoctoral researcher, my role is to investigate a way to filter packets using DNS packets and implement it on BIND9.
- o [Keywords] Domain Name System, DNS over TLS (DoT), DNS over HTTPS (DoH), Packet filtering.

#### Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis

Project Manager, System Designer, Programmer

Mar 2021 — Nov 2021

(Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))

- o [Role] As a doctoral student, I took on the role of project manager and designed the entire system aimed at detecting anomalies or attacks in IoT networks. In addition to designing the system, I implemented an autoencoder model to distinguish between abnormal and normal IoT network traffic.
- o [Keywords] Internet of Things (IoT), Machine learning, Abnormal detection.

## SKILLS

**Tools and Languages** Python (proficient), C/C++, Java, Go, Spark, Hadoop, Git, ŁTFX, Linux OS

DNS, DNS Security (i.e., DNSSEC, DoT, DoH), SMTP, Email Security (i.e., STARTTLS), PKI, DANE, TLS, IoT, **Knowledge Background** 

Edge computing

Communication English, Korean (native)